Sansa!
Heel, heel, heel.
Dogs! No, dogs, come here.
Bollocks.
Piggly squats.
Hello, piggies.
How are you all?
Piggies!
These are the girls,
they're very playful.
These are all the
pregnant mothers.
It was now early March,
and the explosion of
newborn Piggly Squat piglets
was due to hit the
farm at any moment.
Are you
going to give birth?
Also, as it was March,
Kaleb was busy with the spring crops
and I'd come up with an idea which
I thought might help him along.
We're
running out of space.
- What's in here?
- Fertiliser.
What? What the fuck?
I bought a hovercraft.
Talk to me!
Well, as you
know, I love hovercrafts.
My plan is... He
doesn't know this yet.
I know you're stunned.
- A little bit.
- It's for you.
And, as
odd as that sounded,
I wasn't actually
talking nonsense.
Hovercraft are making a
bid to be the farmer's best friend.
There's no more of that
dead weight on the axles
and the truck moves with ease
over the muddiest surface.
That means the farmer can get
his work done when he wants,
whereas with an ordinary
tractor, it would be impossible.
Now there's a hopeless position
for you. Well and truly stuck.
Temper, temper!
You can always get one of those
hover trucks with a bit of skirt.
My plan was simple:
If we used a hovercraft to spray
the crops with fertiliser...
Perfect.
Then we could do away with the
tramlines that normal sprayers need,
so we could plant crops where
those tramlines normally go.
I did the calculation
last night.
Do you know how many miles of
tramline there are on this farm?
- How many miles?
- 54.
- What?
- 54 miles of tramline.
And they're about that wide.
So that adds up to...
Well, I did the cost of lost
crop. It's £5,200 a year.
- Wow.
- Now, with this, no tramlines.
Obviously, I then
had to explain to Kaleb
that operating a hovercraft
is a bit more tricky
than driving a tractor.
So you've
got two engines.
Yeah.
This is your lift engine,
that fills the skirt with air.
Then, once you've got the lift,
you start your
right-hand engine.
This is your throttle.
Okay. It's not the brake?
No. You have no brakes.
Right? You see,
these are your handlebars.
- You see they turn the flaps on the back.
- Okay, yeah. Yeah.
They make no difference.
- Okay.
- Absolutely no difference.
If you see an obstacle, and you
do that, you're going to hit it.
You have to lean. So basically,
you're either like this...
You sort of lean, get
right over like that.
- And that steers it?
- And that will make it go right.
And then, get over
like that, and that...
Get as much weight as
you can, as far over.
- And that'll steer it.
- And that'll steer it along with...
- That.
- The handlebars.
But effectively, you've no
braking and no steering.
Okay. Can I have a go
before I start spraying?
Yes, I think that's
a very good idea.
This feels so good,
telling you what to do.
Oh, now it's going.
Wow!
Lean!
Hang on... I'm leaning!
Oh, my God!
Come on, man, you're
supposed to going in a straight line.
This is useless!
That's as
straight as a roundabout!
All right, turn!
Lean!
Lean and power!
My young apprentice
is doing well.
I've got it.
Fallen out.
He's fallen out.
Ah!
Not good.
Come on, you clown.
I need to learn this
shit, I'm going spraying.
Turn, turn, turn,
turn, turn, turn, turn, turn.
You see, it's just
gliding over the weeds.
Turn, turn,
turn. No... Turn.
We get the spray fitted,
fertiliser applied.
Turn, turn, turn.
All we need to do
is teach him how to stop.
With the driving
lesson successfully concluded,
it was time to test the
hovercraft as a crop sprayer.
Tell you what, you
look like a shit gimp.
- This is liquid...
- Fertiliser.
Liquid nitrate.
- Yeah.
- It's phenomenally corrosive.
Once Kaleb had finished
filling my bespoke fertiliser tanks,
we were ready for the off.
You ready?
Yup.
Go ahead,
my young apprentice.
Yee-haw!
Oh, it's
spraying, it's spraying.
I'm getting
good at this!
Woohoo!
Hey, this isn't bad.
Now just go a little
bit to the left of that.
Yeah. On my way.
But then, after
exactly 75 seconds...
Kaleb, is there any
spray coming out?
No.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
Is that it?
Oh, I'm empty.
- And how big's this field?
- 20 acres.
How many times are you going
to have to refill with fertiliser?
Er... 25 times.
You're joking.
It's going to take me
about 8 hours to spray this field.
That means I've got to spend
8 hours in this gimp suit.
I think we stick to
the sprayer, please.
Can you please undress me?
Cut.
Clearly, I needed bigger
fertiliser tanks on the hovercraft,
which meant it would need
more powerful engines
to deal with the extra weight.
That was a big job.
And there was no time to do it
because the next day
winter came back.
And then
the next night,
our feed from the
cameras in the pigloos
suggested one of the Mums
was about to give birth.
Let's see how
she's getting on.
Look, there's
an actual piglet.
That's her first baby ever.
Oh, I think we've
got a problem here.
Concerned that the piglet
was not finding a teat to drink from,
Lisa went in to help.
Oh my gosh,
there's a teat, there.
Oh, she's on the teat.
Good little one.
It's March 10th, it
shouldn't be this cold.
The climate is changing.
Somebody needs to mention that
because it's really bad.
This is the best bit
of farming I've had so far.
How many will we get?
How many teats has
this one got, 16?
- Yeah, yeah, that's 16.
- So she could have 16 piglets.
This joy, however,
soon turned into concern
because over an hour went by
and no more piglets appeared.
Come on. Come on Mum.
One's not enough.
Come on, you
can do it. Come on.
I was told they were
born like machine gun bullets.
You know they go duh-duh-duh...
Come on Mum.
She's properly wobbling.
I would say that is
a pig in distress.
- The vet's not answering.
- Welcome to the EE voicemail...
And neither is Kaleb.
Shite!
Eventually though,
one of the vets answered.
Hello?
Hi, there. It's Jeremy Clarkson
here at Diddly Squat Farm.
Hum...
Hey, what's going on?
Well, we've got a gilt
who's given birth to one piglet
an hour and 20 minutes ago
and seems to be
in some distress.
And nothing else has come since.
Is that normal, an hour and 20 minutes
between births, or should we be worried?
- An hour and 20, did you say?
- Yeah.
It's usually
much faster than that.
Is she actively pushing or does she
just look like she's moving around?
Does she look uncomfortable?
She looks, I would
say, uncomfortable,
but Lisa keeps telling me
that's how people look...
Well... How creatures look
when they're giving birth.
I mean, she's vibrating
and snorting and...
I'd say it looked
like she's in distress
but I'm a man, I have no idea
what I'm talking about so...
Lisa's gone back to the farm to
see if she can find a rubber glove
and is very happy to pop in
there and have a look... A feel.
Yeah, that might be the
first... the best thing to do,
because it's easier for you to have a
feel and see if you can feel anything.
So yeah, have you got any
lube up there as well?
Lisa will have some lube.
Don't put that on television.
That's fine... if
you go to feel in there
and see if she
can feel a piglet,
if she can feel front
legs or back legs
and they feel like they're
coming in the normal position.
She can give
them a bit of a tug?
Okay. Thanks, Jenny.
Take care, bye. Bye.
I have those, but I also have...
Oh, perfect.
I don't know if I'll be able to
feel much. I think I prefer those.
Okay. Well, let's get in there quickly
because it's nearly two hours now.
According to
Jenny, you put your hand in
and if you can feel legs or head,
you've got to try and tease it out.
If it's sideways, we've
got to give her a call.
Good girl,
good girl, good girl.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
She's stopped.
She's really stopped.
Okay, I'm
in. I'm in, I'm in.
- And?
- I'm in.
- Oh, my God, that's so far up.
- Can you feel a piglet?
I'm not... No. I
really can't feel anything.
They're so far in.
- I'm going to ring Jenny again.
- Please, ring Jenny. I...
Okay,
no, no. Well done.
We can either give
her an injection of oxytocin
which sometimes helps
or in the meantime we can get
her up and walk her around.
What? Get her out and walk her?
If you try and get her
and move her around a little bit
- sometimes it stimulates everything.
- Okay.
Oh, nice.
It's so cold.
Come on, pig.
She's not going to in a million
years. She's in lab our.
Did the vet say:
"Just walk her around"?
When you were in lab our, if
someone had come in with a Maccy D,
you wouldn't have said: "Oh,
I'll follow that." You wouldn't.
- No, although she's a pig.
- Oh, she's coming!
I can't believe it!
She's actually in lab our
and she's come
out for a Maccy D.
Hum...
I'm bonding. I'm
bonding with my piglet.
No, don't let her in.
No! She's treading on me.
No! Fucking hell,
what's going on?
I can't find... The
pig has beaten me.
Jesus.
I've been in a wrestling
match with a pig.
- In you go.
- Lisa?
We've got to get
her out for a walk.
That's what the vet said.
- Lisa.
- She's having huge contractions.
She's been for a walk
and she's having...
She hasn't been for a
walk!
If I did that, you
wouldn't call that a walk.
It's coming. It's coming,
it's coming. We have a piglet. Yes!
It's steaming, it's steaming!
She's steaming, there's steam.
It's a big piglet.
There
you go, come here.
Come here slithery girl.
That's two.
There's a fart.
That's another piglet coming.
- Is it?
- Yup.
Pig coming. Pig coming.
Yes, look. Pig three.
Lisa, he's attached... she's
attached to her mother. What do I do?
What, what, what?
- She's attached with a stringy thing.
- No, that's fine,
it's the umbilical cord. It's part
of it. It's part of the process.
- Go on, lick it.
- Oh, my God, it's so cute.
Three pigs!
Good mother.
Over the next couple
of hours, seven more were born.
And after a quick nap,
we came back to see how
everything was going.
Morning, piggies.
Well done, Mum.
Ten piggies.
- Jeremy?
- What?
There's one here not
moving. Have a look. Can you go in?
Oh no.
Are they okay?
Darling, are they okay?
Oh no, it's a big healthy
one too. Did you get...
Did you get laid on?
Oh no.
Lisa?
Whoa! She's just sat on another one.
Oh, look...
She's obviously
squashing them.
They're perfect.
You're a big lovely one.
And you're a sweet little sow.
So we've got
two, three, four, five.
Wait a minute, seven.
She's lying on one.
There's only seven.
Shit! Shit, shit, shit.
- Where's the other one gone?
- Behind you.
I think she's
lying on one of them again.
- Okay, yeah.
- Yes, there is one behind her.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
She's squashed it again.
- You are a shit mother.
- No, she's not.
She is. She was
lying on one of them.
That's how 2 of them
have obviously died.
- But she's shattered.
- Look, there it is.
Three, four, five, six, seven,
eight. Right, they're all...
That's better, now.
You mustn't sit
on your children.
You do realise we've got this
every night now for a week.
We kind of messed up, didn't we?
- We did.
- Yeah.
Sure
enough, that night...
Another sow started
giving birth.
But this time to a
litter of only three.
How are you doing, Mum?
So now...
The first one gave birth to ten,
sat on two of them, so
we're down to eight.
Nine, ten, eleven.
And one has been born
down here, this morning.
That's 12.
She is so enormous.
Oh, look at you! Yes.
So we've got Clumsy Pig, that sat on
two of her piglets and killed them.
Swiz Pig,
that promised to deliver
10 or 12 or 16 piglets
and delivered only three.
And now we've got Unit Pig!
There was... How
did that happen?
I was literally talking to the
camera man for two seconds,
I've looked back in there and
there's another one come out.
This is a good pig,
she's birthing well.
Lisa arrived just in time
to see Unit pop number three out.
There's another one!
Oh!
Come on out. Come on, come on.
By the end of the morning,
Unit had produced ten piglets.
And because she was an experienced
Mum who'd had litters before,
she seemed to know
what she was doing.
Well done, Mum!
However, when
we checked in later on...
We've got one,
two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine.
Oh...
Fuck it.
Oh no.
Oh...
I can't bear it. Another one.
- She's obviously squidged it.
- Yeah...
We then went to
check on the other Mums.
- And then this is eight left.
- Yeah.
Because two died.
There's only seven. She can't
have killed another one.
Oh no...
Oh, for fuck's sake!
Oh my God,
that's so upsetting.
Bottom line,
we'd now lost four piglets
as well as three of the five
surprises that had come along
just over two months earlier.
Oh, they're adorable.
- Seven piglets have died.
- Out of?
Twenty-eight. A quarter
of them have died.
What are we doing wrong?
Worried that we were indeed
making some terrible mistake...
- Hi.
- How are you?
Vanessa.
We consulted our
neighbours, Vanessa and Andy,
who'd been pig
farmers for years.
Seven piglets, 25% of
the piglets have been squashed,
- which is a lot, isn't it?
- Yes, it is.
But I mean, how...
Mothers
sitting on them.
Okay. I mean, it's not uncommon.
They are
classically terrible mothers.
Some are worse than others.
This breed is
classically terrible?
Yes.
Well, and pigs
in general just...
One thing about the arcs is that
if they're in a big house
altogether with other sows,
the other sows do sort of tell
the one who's sat on her piglets.
They will make some
fuss. They notice it.
If you've got a bad mother,
the others will tell them it.
Having processed
this information,
we then spoke with Kaleb.
The biggest problem is,
the piglets are cold.
Now, when the Mum lays down...
The Mum stands up to go and eat, the
piglets are going: "Fuck, it's cold."
It's cold, so they
find each other.
And then the pig comes back
in, the sow comes back in,
then they find the
warmth automatically.
So when the pig
starts to lay down,
- it's trying to get near the warmth ASAP.
- Of the pig.
Do you see what I mean?
- It was bloody cold last night.
- Yeah.
And this is why you're
losing so many piglets.
It's not because you're a bad
pig farmer, you're really good.
And I'm being nice. You
are good. You are good.
So now we knew
why the piglets were dying,
but we couldn't work
out what to do about it.
And that night, we lost another.
And we had a new problem,
because the remaining pregnant
sow was showing absolutely no sign
of giving birth.
Her milk hasn't even come down.
How can she be so far behind?
She could be barren.
Shall we call her Barren?
Baroness.
Well, this is your
favourite one, this is.
Yes, this is my
friend. She's so gentle.
She's very lovely.
She was also
eating very little,
so we called out Jenny the vet.
- So this is our poorly pig.
- She's very sweet.
I hear she's not eating very well,
so that can't be good for anybody.
It means we should
hopefully be close.
Doubtless, Lisa will now arrange for it
to be taken away in a luxury ambulance
and put into a kind
of pig nursing home
with streaming
television to watch.
She's had that
food in front of her now
for 12 hours or more. 18 hours?
And she kind of sits there,
and she doesn't even move.
She kind of puts her tongue
out, almost, and takes a bit.
She snuffles up a bit, she
doesn't eat like a pig.
Yeah, which makes me
think that something's not right.
- She does look really not very happy...
- Yeah.
In the way she's moving.
She's got a rasp in her breathing
when you're listening to her lungs,
so I'm wondering whether she's got
a touch of infection going on there.
So what I probably
will be inclined to do
is give her an anti-inflammatory,
give her an antibiotic,
see how she goes.
Sorry, darling, you're not
going to like this very much.
Good girl.
Okay, she's done.
Well done.
She's pregnant, right?
She definitely
looks really heavy down low,
which suggests that
she might be pregnant.
So that's good. Good girl!
- Thanks, Jenny.
- Let us know if she's not getting better.
Yeah, will do.
While we were waiting anxiously
for Baroness to go into lab our,
bigger events were
unfolding around us.
Down at West Oxfordshire
District Council,
a government inspector had arrived
to adjudicate on our appeal
against the enforcement notice.
We'd been advised not to attend,
so instead, we
went into overdrive
to make sure everything in
the farm shop was super local,
council compliant and
completely above board.
This... Ned, who works for
us, he's just turned sixteen,
these are his biscuits, he
makes them on his own kitchen.
Granola, that's a
girl down the road.
Flour comes from that
field over there.
These are all made
up in our kitchen.
This, a neighbour
down the road makes.
This... This is Mrs. Viktor.
Viktor does our honey,
And Mrs. Viktor makes
her soap using our honey.
This is using...
Our delicious jerky
using our chillies again. We're
growing more chillies this year.
These are made in Chipping
Norton from a local baker.
This... This is made
using our wheat.
Err... Over here this is our
gin. That's made in Burford.
The pottery is made
from a local lady.
So this is our past chilli...
The programme's only 40 minutes
long and you've been 28 minutes...
Shush then.
Of equal importance
was the future of the burger van
because with no restaurant,
this had become the only way of
selling our beef and pork at a profit.
I need a burger and a
truffle and parmesan for this, chef.
Thank you.
Annie, who runs the van, had
been to the council hearing that day
to plead the case for her
business to stay open.
Vomit, what's it like?
It's a big room,
and then there are,
at the back of the room,
sort of, twelve rows
of eight across seats with
an aisle down the middle.
Then you've got the council on one
side with their legal representation,
and then the guy presiding over
the top of all looking down at you.
- Has he got a beard?
- No.
Oh, that's good.
You go in.
I was late because of a severe
lack of parking, the irony.
So I went in and found
a seat next to Emma,
who does the milk, so I thought
at least I've got an ally.
And then he said would anyone
from the floor like to comment?
I stood up and I said:
"My name is Annabel Gray,
I grew up in a
farming community.
I lived in the countryside
most of my life.
Now I run the catering
trailer behind Diddly Squat."
At which point there was
a gasp around the room.
360s.
I was like: "Oh,
gosh. Here we go."
And I said: "I'm really
passionate about this.
You have got something which
could be a massive asset.
Yes, it's not perfect, you
know. I hide no secrets.
There are stuff we
need to deal with,
but no one knows what you're
next going to get upset about.
So give us the infrastructure
to make it something brilliant."
Exactly. They said we could
have one lavatory, that was sufficient.
And they said that nine car
parking spaces were sufficient.
The council guy that I've just
witnessed is saying based on ten spaces,
everyone get in, get out the car,
you've got five minutes to run round.
If you wanna grab something,
you've got to be back in your
car in five minutes and out.
- In and out in five minutes?
- In five minutes. Yeah.
So if somebody disabled turns up, I
don't know how quickly he can get out.
Let's time him next time.
"You've got five minutes."
But did you get a sense of
how it's going down there?
Are they still trying to
claim it isn't a farm shop?
Yeah, they're saying that
people come and buy things
but actually, it's an
entertainment and leisure facility.
This is what pisses me off
though because I look at that...
Every single thing.
I know where that bread
came from, the wheat, the beer.
And I look out there
and see your operation.
And that's where all the meat
goes that's cooked in bread
- that's also made with wheat from here.
- In the farms.
And you think it couldn't
be more of a farm.
Admittedly, when
it first started,
we were taking the piss
slightly, but now...
But I did love when
the council said
people are driving past other
farm shops which are better.
And you just think,
our cows are grass-fed.
Yeah.
Nurtured through the winter,
the highest possible quality
and the council...
And it's not really
their business.
They're saying: "Go to another farm
shop, they have better quality produce."
And if they close you
down, we have no way...
If you get closed, we're fucked.
Anyway, thank you ever so much.
Chadlington football shirt.
"My shirt is better
than your shirt."
I like that.
Oh, Lisa! These are my
scales from the kitchen.
- Lisa!
- What?
These are my scales
from the kitchen.
- No, no, no.
- Yes, they are!
- Yes, they are. I couldn't find them.
You've nicked my scales.
I might have needed to borrow
them for a little bit for the veg.
Why don't you buy
the shop a pair?
Because it's up here now.
I couldn't
find those anywhere.
- You don't need to weigh a chicken.
- You do!
You go "That's about 3 pounds," put it
in the oven and see when it's cooked.
Yes, which is why I always have
salmonella when you've cooked.
- Well, why don't you cook?
- I do fucking cook!
- Well then, you won't get salmonella.
- That's why...
I can't weigh anything.
I never know how much anything
weighs. I wondered where they'd gone.
They're very good by the way.
Having followed
proceedings closely,
Charlie reckoned it would be weeks
before the inspector made a decision.
So all we could do was
get back to farming.
Except we couldn't.
In mid-March, it
started to rain,
and it didn't stop for days.
This hit Kaleb especially hard
because it was too wet to
plant his most valuable crop.
The durum wheat is
our big money crop,
and it could pull a lot of money,
especially for my board this year,
it might potentially be
profit and loss, so...
We've grown it for the last two years
and we've seen how good it can be,
but annoyingly you need to
get it in in perfect timing
because if you don't, it
suffers through the summer
and then the yields
are normally down.
Hum... I wanted to... Yeah.
It's never going to stop
raining, I don't think.
The endless wetness meant
we couldn't work on the dam either.
Not a chance.
It's a lot
of water, isn't it?
It's basically
washed the clay away, look.
Well, we've got to wait for the
water to go down. We cannot...
Yeah.
I agree.
I wanna go farming.
- You can't, it's raining.
- I know.
There was though some
good news from the pig wood,
because thankfully there had
been no more piglet deaths.
Baroness, though, still
hadn't gone into lab our.
And despite a week of antibiotics,
she was clearly no better.
Slept outside last night
because she's so hot.
She's not eating at all.
I don't know what
we're doing wrong.
Something, right?
I mean...
This is...
It's heart-breaking.
Oh, Jenny's here, look.
Still unwell?
Yeah.
- She slept outside last night.
- Yeah.
So her temperature went down
probably because she slept outside.
- Yeah.
- But her breathing is laboured.
Yeah, I'll take
the second temperature.
But it could be that
if she's got pregnant
and then had the
piglets die inside,
they might not be triggering
her to give birth,
but they might be sitting there,
- rotting inside her.
- What do you do in that situation?
Possibly try and induce her
so she'll kick them out.
Without more ado, we
began the inducement procedure.
If the piglets are dead,
then we'll just concentrate
on getting her well again,
- and then...
- Yeah. Yeah.
Behind the ear. Inject.
- Is that it?
- Yeah.
So three o'clock tomorrow,
with the second injection,
which you'll do.
Yeah, I can do that.
It only should be a small amount, not
like that big antibiotic injection.
No, exactly.
So you've only got a small amount
and it should go really easily.
Okay, that's fine.
I'm going
to give her this
and then in four to
twelve hours' time,
she should be starting
to give birth.
There we go. Oh, my
God, hello my friend.
Done.
Yup!
By late afternoon,
the medicine started to work,
and she gave birth to a
piglet that was alive.
But there were still problems.
So the whole
process has started.
She's given birth to
one really small piglet.
She has no milk,
and the piglet is in there
just looking for a teat
and there's no food.
How are we doing?
She's had
one, she has no milk.
Look at that.
Oh, Jesus.
It's absolutely tiny.
- Have we got any pig milk? Like SMA?
- No.
I mean, that's not
a healthy piglet, is it?
Hello,
veterinary clinic.
- Hi, Nathan?
- Hi, there.
Hi, it's Jeremy
Clarkson up at Diddly Squat.
Oh, yeah.
Sorry to trouble you. I gather both
Dilwyn and Jenny are not there,
so I'm troubling you.
- I don't...
- That's all right.
I don't know if you're
up to speed on our sickly sow.
She's popped a piglet out
that is the size of a mouse.
She's not producing any milk.
I was wondering if you
had any suggestions.
So basically, if she's
not letting down any milk,
it's because she's
not producing any.
So, the next step is
basically going to be
bottle feeding the piglets
with some colostrum.
Colostrum? Where do
we get colostrum from?
So, I think in this case it
would probably be easiest if we use
a sort of pre-made
lamb colostrum.
So I think what we'll do is
we'll put some up at the
practice for you to collect
and it will be a case of
following the instructions on it,
mixing it up and bottle
feeding the piglets with it.
All right,
Nathan, thanks. Bye, bye.
No worries,
take care now, bye.
A member of the film
crew went off to get the formula
and then Kaleb arrived...
- Is she still trying to push?
- Yeah.
Just as Baroness
gave birth to piglet number 2.
Oh! Yes, another one.
Is there another one?
Yeah, we
have another one.
Is it alive?
Yeah. There we go.
God, is that
one even smaller? Yeah.
That one is unbelievably tiny.
"I'm fucking
hungry!" I bet you are.
This one is
weak as hell, Kaleb.
One of them is as weak as hell.
That runt,
that little tiny one?
No, the bigger one. She
can't open her mouth.
She's just, you know... Her head's
flopping around on the nipple.
Luckily, the formula
milk was now ready to go.
All right. Well done.
- That's it.
- Almost.
Good.
That's perfect.
We'll make
you a big strong pig.
We'll have you up
and about in no time.
Then Nathan arrived and
started to work vet miracles.
We've got one.
- He's okay?
- Yup, alive.
Here we go, another one.
- Lisa?
- Yes?
- How many now?
- Four.
- Are they all alive?
- Yes.
- Are they tiny?
Hang on.
I've got another one.
Soon, Baroness
was mother to five piglets.
I'm just going to put them
all next to Mum for a bit of warmth.
Because he's a bit cold there.
Just pop them all together.
And having
bottle fed them all,
we went home to
grab a bit of sleep.
The next morning,
we found that three of
the piglets had died.
They'd simply been
too weak to survive.
We moved the remaining two
to a heated pen at the farm,
but even that wasn't working.
Another dead one.
Oh!
- Is that the only one that's left?
- We've got one more.
How's the
mother? Is she okay?
She's still alive.
We're losing a lot of piglets.
- What?
- We're losing a lot of piglets.
It's really tough, isn't it?
And this one, we just have to feed
this one every 10 minutes or something.
I can't remember
what the vet said.
Come here, you.
We've still got a feisty one.
Is this the one
that was born second?
I've lost count.
I honestly don't know.
We'll make it our life's mission
to make that piglet survive.
Yeah.
And her mother.
The mother will survive.
I'll go down and see her now.
You're going down?
That night we did what even
the most hard-hearted farmer will do
at a time like this.
Come on. There we go.
We took the sickly piglet into
our kitchen to look after it there.
There we go.
Come on.
Still a bit small.
It's still a bit cold to be
honest. Your ears are cold.
Okay, let's pop
you back in there.
Okay, get nice and warm. Yeah.
Now, I'm not going
to put you in,
but it's just a lot warmer here, okay?
I know. I'm sorry.
There we go, okay?
The next
day, irony of ironies,
we had to go to the farm shop
to meet Andy Garcia the butcher.
There's lots of it.
Let's take a look at it.
He'd finished preparing the
pigs I'd recently taken to slaughter.
Seven boxes, two
pigs' worth of pork in these.
You should be doing the lifting,
really. They're your pigs.
You're young and I've
seen you hold a pram
- while aiming your gun at Al Capone.
- Look at that. This is your favourite.
- These are belly pork strips.
- Yum.
Pork chops there.
You can tell they're really nice pigs
because of the amount of fat on them.
Whoever's looking after
them is doing a great job.
Erm... You can see that they're
going to eat really well.
Lots of sausages.
Holy moly.
Carolina Reaper
and honey sausages.
- Oh, my giddy aunt.
- There's another box.
Two pigs have produced
4, 8.
- Jesus!
- There's 36 packs of six in a box.
Jeremy, Sandy and
Black Forest Sausages.
- Sounds good.
- Sounds good doesn't it.
This is so
good for my side of the chart.
God, strewth, that's brilliant.
Except it is so... One of the things
I can't get my head around is,
we're having a really tottering
time with the piglet births.
Hmm.
- Really tottering.
- Hmm-hmm.
So you're up all night, sort of nurturing
these pigs and trying to make them warm,
trying to make them comfortable
and trying to make them alive.
Yeah.
And then you break off...
to come here and
receive all this.
Yeah.
Mixed emotions.
There's only one expression I can
think of, and it's farmer logic.
'Cause you love animals. All
farmers love their animals.
- And then they kill them and sell them.
- Hmm.
This way you can love them twice.
Back at the farm, as
the rain continued to fall,
I brought the poorly
piglet into my office
so I could keep an eye on
her while I was working.
I've moved her away from the
Aga and brought her next to
the stove in the barn.
And she's really not well.
Hey.
No...
- She's the last one.
- I know.
I know, come on.
No?
It's okay, little one.
I'm with you, okay?
You can go, I'll stay with you.
- And her mother's not well either.
- I know.
She's worse than she was
before, to be honest.
She is.
I just find that heart-breaking.
Hi, Jenny.
- Hi, Jenny.
- Hi, there.
Another familiar sight.
- I've heard she's not doing well.
- Yeah.
No, I'm afraid she's
passed. There's nothing there.
- Did she come out very little?
- Yeah.
But...
I can't do this. I can't
have pigs anymore, honestly.
- A nightmare. I like them too much.
- Hmm.
Unbelievably,
the torment wasn't over.
Because we then had to turn
our attention to Baroness,
now that every single one
of her piglets had died.
Hello,
darling. Hi, sweet pea.
Good girl.
What are
you doing now, Jenny?
Just taking her temperature,
to see whether she has got a fever.
She's very wobbly though.
- She's walking like she's drunk.
- She's really wobbly.
Yeah. Look.
You can see her
swaying from side to side.
She hasn't eaten. She's had a
bit of water, and that's it.
You can see on the back end. Her
bum should be round with muscle.
It's really straight
up and down.
She's obviously lost a huge amount
of muscle there and support.
And the problem is,
especially on this terrain,
where she's up and down hills
and it's all a bit lumpy bumpy,
I'm really worried that she's
going to get to the point
that she's just going
to go off those legs
and collapse.
It could be something cancerous.
The other thing you
could be dealing with
is if you've got some
damage to the liver.
Neither of which are...
- Curable.
- Yeah.
Is she suffering now?
Any animal that's not
eating is not in a good state.
She's so unsteady
on her feet, isn't she?
If you don't make
the decision now,
I have a feeling that we'll be in
this position in another week's time
with her collapsed down
the bottom of there.
If she's not going to get
better and she's suffering,
it's Dignitas time.
Yeah.
So if you want me
to do the deed,
then I'll sort it out,
and then you'll need to get
someone in to take her away
- after everything's done.
- When would you do the deed?
I can do it now,
if you would like.
Fucking hell.
- What do you think?
- I can give you a bit of time.
I don't want her to be unhappy,
in pain, or to get sicker.
- And then...
- You don't want her to die either.
I don't want her to die with a
broken leg having fallen down there
and just be all
crumpled up and alone.
I know. It's always
a really difficult decision.
She's so lovely.
She does seem like she's
got a bit of a sweet nature.
She's really sweet. She's
always been the sweetest.
Yeah.
Well...
Yeah? Time?
It's fine. You don't have to be
present if you don't want to be.
- Yeah. I don't want to see it.
- No.
- Thanks, Jenny.
- That's not a problem. Okay.
Bye, Baroness.
Oh, God...
All right, darling.
Time's up, I'm afraid.